Nolan Adams

I am a creative and capable Electrical Engineering student with real-world engineering experience at both a personal and professional level. I have also developed leadership and communication skills from an early age, allowing me to work well with just about anyone.

nolan (at) nadams.net nadams.net Canton, MI

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- CAD Modeling AutoCAD/Fusion 360, SolidWorks
- Programming (intermediate) C/C++, Python, HTML/CSS
- Computers Linux/Unix, macOS, Windows
- 3D Printing & Prototyping
- Fabrication Power tools, light machining
- Troubleshooting

EXPERIENCE

Application Engineering InternAug. 2021 - Present

Robert Bosch, LLC

Working with the Parking Systems Application Engineering team, collaborating with clients to deliver effective systems for products.

Receiver / Stocker July 2020 - Aug. 2021

Lowes Home Improvement, LLC

I was tasked with stocking merchandise, receiving and unloading shipments, and operating power equipment.

FIRST Robotics Intern June 2019 - Aug. 2019

Robert Bosch, LLC

I was an intern working with the Application and Test Engineering teams to test vehicle calibrations.

FIRST Robotics Team - Group Lead Jan. 2015 - May 2019

FRC Team #862 - Lightning Robotics

Electrical Lead (May 2017 - May 2018)

Control Systems Lead (May 2018 - May 2019)

EDUCATION

University of Michigan - Dearborn *GPA 3.78* Sept. 2019 - Present

Pursuing B.S.E. in Electrical Engineering

Salem High School *GPA 3.77* Sept. 2015 - June 2019

Took classes related to engineering and other technical disciplines

Nolan Adams

I am a creative and capable Electrical Engineering student with real-world engineering experience at both a personal and professional level. I have also developed leadership and communication skills from an early age, allowing me to work well with just about anyone.

nolan (at) nadams.net nadams.net Canton, MI

ACTIVITIES / ACHIEVEMENTS

FIRST Robotics Aug. 2013 - June 2019

FTC Team 7313 (Aug. 2013 - Dec. 2015)

FRC Team 862 (Jan. 2015 - June 2019)

Tang Soo Do (Martial Arts) 2007 - 2014

Black Belt (Dec. 2013)

Mentoring FIRST Robotics teams Sept. 2015 - Present

FTC Teams 7313 / 7325 / 9841 / 9842 (Sept. 2015 - Dec. 2018)

FRC Team 862 (Aug. 2021 - Present)

Volunteering and community service 2015 - Present

through FIRST

Designed, built, and programmed a Mar. 2017 - Dec. 2017

sensor test bench for robotics team